<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luke Matthew Perez on Luke Matthew Perez</title>
    <link>https://lukemperez.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Luke Matthew Perez on Luke Matthew Perez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 luke m perez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Irony of Technological War</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/publication/niebuhr_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 09:13:49 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/publication/niebuhr_2015/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week in Review</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/week-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 07:45:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/week-in-review/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reading&#34;&gt;Reading:&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://providencemag.com/2017/04/libya-intervention-just-war-unjustly-disowned/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;A just war unjustly disowned&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Gobush on the moral tragedy of doing nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.realcleardefense.com/articles/2017/04/19/five_things_that_helped_carl_von_clausewitz_become_a_great_strategic_thinker_111208.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How Clausewitz became a great strategic thinker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vanya Eftimova Bellinger explains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The French Revolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mentorship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good partner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time (for ideas to mature).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://duckofminerva.com/2017/04/will-moore-a-students-perspective.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Will More: A student&amp;rsquo;s perspective&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sadness I feel now as I write this is that he won’t get to see the ways he changed and is changing the discipline. He won’t get to see how his intellectual offspring flourish. I’m sad that he won’t continue to make us all a little better. He’s right about a lot of things, including how this world treats anyone who isn’t typical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge loss for the discipline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;listening&#34;&gt;Listening&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/espnradio94-1/lolo-jones-4-13-17?utm_source=soundcloud&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=twitter&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Lolo Jones on ESPN&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hoover.org/research/conflict-syria&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Libertarian&amp;rdquo; with Richard A. Epstein&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Epstein talks about the recent strikes and U.S. foreign policy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Info Session: Student Professional Development Fund</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/info-session-student-professional-development-fund/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 14:57:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/info-session-student-professional-development-fund/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Quick note for UT undergraduate and graduate students who are interested in National Security. This week, The Clements Center is holding a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.clementscenter.org/events/item/1121-spdf-info&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Student Professional Development Fund Info Session&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;!---more--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short of it is, if you find an unpaid internship in National Security, the Clements Center has funds to help you pay for living expenses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cryptocurrencies: Challenges, disruption &amp; Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/cryptocurrencies-challenges-disruption--opportunities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 15:51:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/cryptocurrencies-challenges-disruption--opportunities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lukemperez.com/img/cpg-crypto.png&#34; alt=&#34;Cryprocurrencies&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This week at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.utcpg.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Politics and Governance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Details&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Wednesday, April 19, 5:00&amp;ndash;6:00PM&lt;br /&gt;
Student Activity Center (SAC), Room 1.106&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptocurrencies and the decentralized computing networks that power them, such as Bitcoin and Ethereum, have become a global phenomenon. The problem is, most people, including policymakers, don&amp;rsquo;t have a deep understanding of how these new networks operate, what they can do, and what risks and opportunities they present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.petervv.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Peter Van Valkenburgh&lt;/a&gt;, Research Director at Coin Center, will explain how cryptocurrencies work, examine the many policy issues they raise, and discuss the future of this innovative yet disruptive technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event is free and open to the public, but your RSVP is requested. Light refreshments will be served, and parking is available in the Manor Garage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP Today: &lt;a href=&#34;UTCPG419.eventbrite.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UTCPG419.eventbrite.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End Strategic Restraint</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/the-end-strategic-restraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 14:24:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/the-end-strategic-restraint/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mike Pence says &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.realcleardefense.com/articles/2017/04/17/era_of_strategic_patience_is_over_111189.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;the era of strategic restraint is over.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pointing to the quarter-century since the United States first confronted North Korea over its attempts to build nuclear weapons, the vice president said a period of patience had followed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;But the era of strategic patience is over,&amp;rdquo; Pence declared. &amp;ldquo;President Trump has made it clear that the patience of the United States and our allies in this region has run out and we want to see change. We want to see North Korea abandon its reckless path of the development of nuclear weapons, and also its continual use and testing of ballistic missiles is unacceptable.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always viewed Obama&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;strategic restraint&amp;rdquo; line as hand-waving for &amp;ldquo;we don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do anything about the problem&amp;rdquo;, but it remains unclear at this point whether the Jacksonian impulse is the proper re-engagement on national security.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Easter Joy</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/easter-joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Apr 2017 06:43:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/easter-joy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lukemperez.com/img/Nacho_Easter_Running.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Easter Joy&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kiddo enjoyed his &amp;ldquo;first&amp;rdquo; Easter this weekend. At 18 months, he&amp;rsquo;s now self-aware of the fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPSA 2017</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/mpsa-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2017/04/mpsa-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://lukemperez.com/img/seminary-coop.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Seminary Coop&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;midwest-post-mortem&#34;&gt;Midwest post-mortem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I attended the Midwest Political Science Association annual conference in Chicago. AS conferences go, I was pleased with the event and the payoff was well worth the time and energy it cost to attend. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;jss&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;JSS&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, the organizers placed my paper in the &lt;em&gt;Junior Scholar Symposium&lt;/em&gt; (JSS), which is not an actual paper presentation but a round-table seminar. Each presenter is obligated to read the papers of everyone else and prepare feedback. Also, rather than a chair and discussant, two discussants are assigned who are senior scholars in the field. My paper, &amp;ldquo;For (God and) Country&amp;rdquo;, examines the rise of international religious freedom as an objective of U.S. foreign policy. What I presented was essentially a truncated and distilled version of what is my dissertation. I argue that international religious freedom has long been an integral component to American grand strategy throughout the 20th century. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more pleased with the process. Our senior discussants were terrific and, at least for me, provided feedback that will help make this project more analytically rigorous than it would otherwise be. Feedback at early stages of projects can often be more helpful because &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/5895898&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;thrashing at early stages is easy&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to my colleagues who participated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soumi Chatterjee, UCLA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brittnay L. Wood, WSU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fernanda B. Almedia, WSU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discussants:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Christopher, F. Gelpi, Ohio State&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vinicius R. Vieria, Princeton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;latino-caucus-networking&#34;&gt;Latino Caucus &amp;amp; Networking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some years ago, I applied for a travel grant for Latino scholars. I wanted to go to Rome and hit some archives on Augustine for my master&amp;rsquo;s thesis at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www1.villanova.edu/villanova/artsci/psc.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Villanova&lt;/a&gt;. What I didn&amp;rsquo;t know was that the Latino Caucus exists primarily to help promote scholarship on Latino politics&amp;mdash;but that didn&amp;rsquo;t stop them from funding part of my airfare. And although my work has never fit with the prevailing interests of the Caucus, I have nevertheless been thankful for their support over the years. So I do my best to pay it forward, and in doing so I have made a number of acquaintances and friendships over the years. This year was no exception. I met &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lsu.edu/hss/polisci/graduate_students/graduate_students/vitelag.php&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Gaby Vitela&lt;/a&gt;, who is doing some interesting work on campaign finance in her dissertation. On Saturday, we attempted to hit up a joint that does Pizza Pot Pies but when we arrived to learn that the wait was 2+ hours, we called an audible. Still, the afternoon let us commiserate with a former classmate of hers and talk all things job market (this fall!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;seminary-co-op&#34;&gt;Seminary Co-Op&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much could be said about this wonderful gem. I never made it to the original bookstore, but I wanted to see it, finally. It&amp;rsquo;s beautiful: one could get lost in wonderful collection of literature, philosophy, and social science collections. It&amp;rsquo;s a masterpiece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Su on International Religious Freedom</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2017/01/su-on-international-religious-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 11:50:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2017/01/su-on-international-religious-freedom/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wonderful new book, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hup.harvard.edu/catalog.php?isbn=9780674286023&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exporting Freedom&lt;/em&gt; (Anna Su 2016)&lt;/a&gt;, on the rise of religious freedom in American foreign policy. Anna Su looks at the construction of the international legal regime during the 20th century and finds that the efforts of promoting international religious freedom long predate the Jackson-Vanik Amendment. Although I&amp;rsquo;m skeptical that some of the early cases could rightly be read into the history of American foreign policy regarding religious freedom, I am open to persuasion and, more importantly, she didn&amp;rsquo;t write this book on the grand strategy of international religious freedom. If she had, I&amp;rsquo;d be back to the drawing board for a dissertation topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strongly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“Rhetoric, the Socratic Method, and Pedagogy”</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/talk/spurs_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 10:23:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/talk/spurs_2016/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dot Emacs</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2016/11/dot-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 11:51:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2016/11/dot-emacs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My 2010 Macbook Pro finally died. I was hoping to get one more year so I could finish the PhD on the same machine I began it with, but alas. While setting up my new machine, I realized how much I benefited from having my &lt;code&gt;.emacs&lt;/code&gt; file on GitHub. So here&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lukemperez/.emacs&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;link in case anyone finds it helpful&lt;/a&gt;. A note of caution that it is a work-in-progress and some of the features are not fully active (like RefTeX) but I&amp;rsquo;ve been too busy with the dissertation to fix it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close the loops</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2016/10/close-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2016/10/close-loops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I presented a best practices workshop on project management for my fellow graduate students. The purpose was to provide younger students in the program with ideas and concepts for managing projects &amp;ldquo;from idea to publication&amp;rdquo;. Preparing my presentation for the workshop afforded me the opportunity to reflect on the principles of productivity that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years. Despite claims to the contrary, both from within and without, the academe is not unlike many other professions: it a profession fundamentally about knowledge work but with functionally infinite demands on otherwise scarce time and attention. For graduate students in particular, productivity wastes are especially pernicious because they are so deceptive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This problem arises from a basic failure to see project
management as anxiety management. Uncompleted tasks and to-do lists, or worse, half-hearted to-do lists, create a cognitive load on the mind that destroys the ability to concentrate and get into what Cal Newport calls &lt;em&gt;deep work&lt;/em&gt;. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the right space to outline the basics of GTD or any task management system; but whatever system one uses will work better if we realize the end goal is to free up the mental bandwidth to concentrate more deeply and more frequently to do the work that matters to us most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lukemperez/Project-Mgt-Short-Course&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Links to my files for my part of the workshop are here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hugo</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2016/05/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 17:16:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2016/05/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;farewell-squarespace&#34;&gt;Farewell Squarespace&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve hosted my webpage on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; since sometime in my second
year at UT Austin. After several years on the platform, I have nothing
but praise for the folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;: their reputation for
up-time, customer service, and all around technical bad-assery is well
deserved. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a web-hosting/web-design company
wherein you can build a beautiful looking site &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; knowing &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt;
HTML, CSS, or anything of that stuff&amp;mdash;and I do mean it: without
any&amp;mdash;then you cannot go wrong with a Squarespace site. But for me,
the time has come to say goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why leave? If I&amp;rsquo;ve been so happy with Squarespace why make the fuss? I
could list a lot of reasons ranging from technical curiosity to summer
boredom or whatever. But really it comes down to handful of several
small but significant reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blog as text files (esp. in Markdown)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needs of modern academics (syntax highlighting, e.g.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost of hosting (esp. for a graduate student)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reproducability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;blogging-as-public-scholarship&#34;&gt;Blogging as public scholarship&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d love to blog, er, post more &amp;ldquo;note&amp;rdquo; on teaching and learning (i.e.,
scholarship) but Squarespace requires new posts come from within the
browser. Sure, I could open Safari, go to my blog, click on new
content, write a new post, and push it to website with a simplicity
that only reinforces everything I&amp;rsquo;ve said above about why
non-programming professionals should take a serious look at the
platform. But Squarespace is a closed system. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even export
my content from their blog except into a Wordpress XML format. Which
raises an interesting question why they make support for Markdown in
the first place, since the whole point of Markdown, as I understand
it, is to have human readable plain text files that can be converted
into HTML when needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-academic&#34;&gt;Modern Academic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Related to the first item is the need to integrate other tools of
modern researchers. Whether it is linking to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; repo or
conceptualizing blog posts as markdown files, working with a variety
of open source tools have become every more integrated into the
workflow of good scholarship. And although Squarespace can do some of
those things, it is now much easier for me to work in an ecosystem of
open, rather than closed systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I need a few things that are not easy to do on their blogging
module. First, as I begin to use R, Python, and other such programming
tools, I need a way to work on a file in Markdown using code blocks to
show my work and then easily convert that &lt;a href=&#34;http://plain-text.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;plain-text&lt;/a&gt; file into
HTML, PDF, or LaTeX as my needs require. Such a workflow is possible
using MS Word, Squarespace, and other tools, but they are not the ones
I use. (I&amp;rsquo;ve not &lt;strong&gt;installed&lt;/strong&gt; Microsoft Word on any computer I&amp;rsquo;ve
owned since 2009 or so.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;costs-of-hosting&#34;&gt;Costs of hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s face it, graduate students make little to nothing. Every dollar
counts. When I started graduate school, I saw paying for my domain
name as a &lt;em&gt;sine qua non&lt;/em&gt; of a good online presence. But I thought I
could &amp;ldquo;roll my own&amp;rdquo; and avoid paying a monthly hosting fee. I had
tinkered with using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tumblr.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt; but found mixed
results: namely, although the hosting was free and the url could be
custom, the layout was garbage for professional engagement. Eventually
I realized that quality can&amp;rsquo;t faked. I needed a professional looking
site. Squarespace delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s changed is that (a) my technical skills are much better than
they were a few years ago and (b) free static hosting on
&lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. Now I can load an entire website to a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; repo
(short for &amp;ldquo;repository&amp;rdquo; if you&amp;rsquo;re not familiar), work a few settings,
and host a website though GitHub. The only catch is that the webpages
must be static rather than dynamic. The difference between the two is
not really a topic for today, but the short of it is that each has
their advantages. Every job needs different tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, the ease of which I can manage my website without paying a
monthly fee was enough to finally push me to fill in a few gaps in my
knowledge of website development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;replicate-research-replicate-blogging-replicate-anything&#34;&gt;Replicate research, replicate blogging, replicate anything&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I already mentioned this above:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://support.squarespace.com/hc/en-us/articles/205814028-Importing-and-exporting-content&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;exporting on Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;
is not easy. I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure at the time of this drafting if I&amp;rsquo;ll
even get my old blog over. Not that it matters since the friction to
getting a post online kept many a thought, good and bad, from seeing
the digital light of day. Still, it&amp;rsquo;s worth repeating: modern scholars
must be able to reproduce their work. If I can&amp;rsquo;t literally email a
plain text file of my blog post, journal article, or whatever to a
colleague for his or her approval, I&amp;rsquo;m not doing my job right. And
having multiple of versions of the same document in different formats
(HTML, .MD, etc.) only increases the likelihood that at some point one
file will become out of sync with the others being edited. Much easier
to simply version control with git, and push the same file, always in
sync, wherever it needs to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello-hugo&#34;&gt;Hello Hugo&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I finally bit the bullet and rebuilt the site as a static webpage
using &lt;a href=&#34;gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and some thoughts from
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kieranhealy.org/blog/archives/2014/02/24/powered-by-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Kieran Healy&amp;rsquo;s post about using Hugo&lt;/a&gt;.
I read repeatedly that the process was fast, but I was still surprised
about how fast. Troubleshooting some terminal issues and downloading
Hugo took more time than it did to port my major content into Hugo&amp;rsquo;s
structure. Now I have a mostly hand-built site that relies on me, my
GitHub, and some off the shelf tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll spare you the overview of command to build a site. If you&amp;rsquo;re
reading this and interested in trying it, I suggest reading the docs
at &lt;a href=&#34;gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. They will certainly be updated by the time that anyone
comes across this post anyway, so there&amp;rsquo;s no need to date my work with
a workflow that will be largely out of date soon anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do recommend, however, spending some time thinking about what themes
for webpage layouts you like best. A lot of folks mistaken conclude
they must build every last piece of code on their websites for it to
really look &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; or for them to say with confidence they have HTML
skills on their CVs and Resumes. But if you think of website themes, which are
built on CSS, as the webpage equivalent to a LaTeX documentclass or
&lt;code&gt;.sty&lt;/code&gt; file, you&amp;rsquo;ll realize there isn&amp;rsquo;t much difference between the
two and, more importantly, no need to completely re-invent the wheel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So three cheers to Squarespace for getting me this far and three more
for &lt;a href=&#34;gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://pages.github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberating Faith</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/project/dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 19:46:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/project/dissertation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;synopsis&#34;&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A study of international religious freedom and American grand strategy during the cold war. It argues that foreign policymakers choose to promote religious liberty in order to promote and construct the liberal international order.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blindsided U.S. Foreign Policy?</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2015/11/a-blindsided-u.s.-foreign-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 21:05:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2015/11/a-blindsided-u.s.-foreign-policy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;blindside-u-s-foreign-policy-http-www-realcleardefense-com-articles-2015-10-13-blindside-us-foreign-policy-108572-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.realcleardefense.com/articles/2015/10/13/blindside_-_us_foreign_policy_108572.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blindside&amp;mdash;U.S. Foreign Policy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My post is up at Real Clear Defense. Close watching required: this issue isn&amp;rsquo;t going to go away any time soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unjustified Destruction: A case from Star Wars</title>
      <link>https://lukemperez.com/2015/11/unjustified-destruction-a-case-from-star-wars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lukemperez.com/2015/11/unjustified-destruction-a-case-from-star-wars/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-destruction-of-alderaan-was-not-justified-http-duckofminerva-com-2015-11-the-destruction-of-alderaan-was-not-justified-html&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://duckofminerva.com/2015/11/the-destruction-of-alderaan-was-not-justified.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The destruction of Alderaan was &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; Justified&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sony Bunch is wrong (this time).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
