<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Professional Development on Luke M Perez</title>
    <link>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/tags/professional-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Professional Development on Luke M Perez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 14:57:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/tags/professional-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Info Session: Student Professional Development Fund</title>
      <link>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/notes/student-pro-dev-2017-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2017 14:57:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/notes/student-pro-dev-2017-info/</guid>
      <description>Quick note for UT undergraduate and graduate students who are interested in National Security. This week, The Clements Center is holding a Student Professional Development Fund Info Session.
The short of it is, if you find an unpaid internship in National Security, the Clements Center has funds to help you pay for living expenses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MPSA 2017</title>
      <link>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/notes/mpsa_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/notes/mpsa_2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/img/seminary-coop.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Seminary Coop&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;midwest-post-mortem&#34;&gt;Midwest post-mortem&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week I attended the Midwest Political Science Association annual conference in Chicago. AS conferences go, I was pleased with the event and the payoff was well worth the time and energy it cost to attend.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hugo</title>
      <link>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/notes/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 17:16:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/notes/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;farewell-squarespace&#34;&gt;Farewell Squarespace&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve hosted my webpage on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; since sometime in my second
year at UT Austin. After several years on the platform, I have nothing
but praise for the folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;: their reputation for
up-time, customer service, and all around technical bad-assery is well
deserved. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a web-hosting/web-design company
wherein you can build a beautiful looking site &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; knowing &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt;
HTML, CSS, or anything of that stuff&amp;mdash;and I do mean it: without
any&amp;mdash;then you cannot go wrong with a Squarespace site. But for me,
the time has come to say goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual APSA</title>
      <link>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/notes/virtual-apsa-postscript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2012 20:13:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>lukemperez.github.io/lukemperez/notes/virtual-apsa-postscript/</guid>
      <description>Would a conference by any other name smell as sweet? Last week the American Political Science Association (APSA) cancelled it annual conference which was to be held in New Orleans because of Hurricane/Tropical Storm Isaac. As as result, thousands of faculty, ABD interviewees, and other attendees suddenly had to think about practical implications of a year without the major conference. In their announcement about the cancellation, APSA suggested that all papers uploaded to SSRN (a public database where scholarly papers can be downloaded), would count for purposes of CV inclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>