<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grand Strategy on Luke M Perez</title>
    <link>https://www.lukemperez.com/tags/grand-strategy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grand Strategy on Luke M Perez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 09:30:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.lukemperez.com/tags/grand-strategy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SPSA, Building the Strategy of Freedom</title>
      <link>https://www.lukemperez.com/talks/2019_01_spsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 09:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lukemperez.com/talks/2019_01_spsa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Building the Strategy of Freedom&amp;rdquo; examines the impact of Jimmy Carter&amp;rsquo;s and Ronald Reagan&amp;rsquo;s national security strategies on international religious freedom. I argue that each attempted to use religious freedom in order to achieve larger national security goals. Carter&amp;rsquo;s moderate success came at a strategic failure (Iranian Revolution and Soviet Invasion of Afghanistan) because he relied on strict substitution of policies. Reagan, however, relied on policy compliments and therefore achieved greater success fusing religious freedom into American grand strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISA Midwest, Defender of the Faith</title>
      <link>https://www.lukemperez.com/talks/2018_11_isa_midwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lukemperez.com/talks/2018_11_isa_midwest/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Defender of the Faith&amp;rdquo; examines the impact of Dwight Eisenhower&amp;rsquo;s national security strategy on international religious freedom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The End Strategic Restraint</title>
      <link>https://www.lukemperez.com/notes/end-strategic-restraint/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2017 14:24:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lukemperez.com/notes/end-strategic-restraint/</guid>
      <description>Mike Pence says the era of strategic restraint is over.
 Pointing to the quarter-century since the United States first confronted North Korea over its attempts to build nuclear weapons, the vice president said a period of patience had followed.
&amp;ldquo;But the era of strategic patience is over,&amp;rdquo; Pence declared. &amp;ldquo;President Trump has made it clear that the patience of the United States and our allies in this region has run out and we want to see change.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Blindsided U.S. Foreign Policy?</title>
      <link>https://www.lukemperez.com/notes/blindside/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2015 21:05:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.lukemperez.com/notes/blindside/</guid>
      <description>Blindside&amp;mdash;U.S. Foreign Policy My post is up at Real Clear Defense. Close watching required: this issue isn&amp;rsquo;t going to go away any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>