<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ethics on Luke M. Perez, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/ethics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ethics on Luke M. Perez, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 20:39:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/ethics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Social Justice, Violence, and the Imago Dei</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/trevon-imago-dei/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2012 20:39:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/trevon-imago-dei/</guid>
      <description>Identity politics as I have always understood it strives to highlight the forms of domination against communities and classes of people who have been systematically marginalized and oppressed. It aims to right those injustices by privileging modes of discourse of the marginalized against the historically privileged (White Males first and foremost). But in countering injustice, do the advocates for social justice go too far?
Writing at Bitch Media, Sharday Mosurinjohn seems to think so.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syria and the Christian Statesman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/syria-christian-statesman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2012 12:04:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/syria-christian-statesman/</guid>
      <description>Western moral ethics has a long tradition of protecting the innocent. At least since the Christian teaching to care for the least among us (Mt 24:40), ethicists have advocated that the responsibility to protect takes a variety of forms, including a central concern for those who are suffering beyond the borders of one&amp;rsquo;s nations. It should not surprise us then, that the strife in Syria and recent “Kony 2012” video have captured the attention of liberal and conservative alike.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
