<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luke M Perez</title>
    <link>http://lukemperez.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Luke M Perez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2016 Luke M Perez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 21:37:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lukemperez.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>teaching</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 21:37:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description> RHE 306 &amp;ldquo;Introduction to Rhetoric and Writing&amp;rdquo; RHE 306 &amp;ndash; Rhetoric &amp;amp; Writing is a course in argumentation that situates rhetoric as an art of civic discourse. It is designed to train students&amp;rsquo; abilities analyzing various positions held in public debate and to advocate your own position effectively.
 Fall 2015 Spring 2016  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rhetoric and Writing 306</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/teaching/rhe_306/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 21:31:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/teaching/rhe_306/</guid>
      <description>RHE 306 &amp;ndash; Rhetoric &amp;amp; Writing is a course in argumentation that situates rhetoric as an art of civic discourse. It is designed to train your abilities analyzing various positions held in public debate and to advocate your own position effectively. You will learn the ethics of responsible argumentation, fair representation of positions with which you disagree, and responsible representation of your views to audiences with particular values or interests. Your work in this course will help you advance the reading and writing skills necessary for academic and professional success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close the loops</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/post/close-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/post/close-loops/</guid>
      <description>Last week I presented a best practices workshop on project management for my fellow graduate students. The purpose was to provide younger students in the program with ideas and concepts for managing projects &amp;ldquo;from idea to publication&amp;rdquo;. Preparing my presentation for the workshop afforded me the opportunity to reflect on the principles of productivity that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years. Despite claims to the contrary, both from within and without, the academe is not unlike many other professions: it a profession fundamentally about knowledge work but with functionally infinite demands on otherwise scarce time and attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close the loops</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/project/gtd_writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 21:21:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/project/gtd_writing/</guid>
      <description>Summary A short course taught at the Department of Government at the University of Texas at Austin. GitHub Repo includes handout and links of suggested readings (and viewings) on time management, creativity, and best practices. I emphasized the iterative nature of writing, stressing the need to manage the shallow work of email, meetings, and the like so that one can focus un-distracted on the Deep Work of writing, coding, and problem solving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hugo</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/post/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 17:16:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/post/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve hosted my webpage on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; since sometime in my second
year at UT Austin. After several years on the platform, I have nothing
but praise for the folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;: their reputation for
up-time, customer service, and all around technical bad-assery is well
deserved. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a web-hosting/web-design company
wherein you can build a beautiful looking site &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; knowing &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt;
HTML, CSS, or anything of that stuff&amp;mdash;and I do mean it: without
any&amp;mdash;then you cannot go wrong with a Squarespace site. But for me,
the time has come to say goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberating Faith: international religious freedom and American Grand Strategy</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/project/liberating-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 19:46:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/project/liberating-faith/</guid>
      <description>Summary My dissertation investigates the rise of religious liberty in American grand strategy. I begin by noting the empirical oddity of America&amp;rsquo;s international religious freedom agenda vis-a-vis other global powers and argue that religious freedom has long been an integral component to American statecraft. Although religion has recently garnered renewed attention from international relations scholars, the subject remains under-theorized. My project seeks to help us understand more fully how American views of liberty have shaped the efforts to remake and rebuild international order.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Irony of Technological War: Reinhold Niebuhr on drone warfare and the just war tradition</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/publication/irony-technology-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 19:30:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/publication/irony-technology-war/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 22:30:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography I am a doctoral candidate in political science with research interests in religion, ethics, and American foreign policy. I am also an aspiring coffee aficionado, part-time audiophile, and photography hobbyist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blindside--U.S. Foreign Policy</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/publication/blindside/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/publication/blindside/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>