<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Luke M Perez</title>
    <link>http://lukemperez.com/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Luke M Perez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2016 Luke M Perez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lukemperez.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>MPSA 2017</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/post/mpsa_2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/post/mpsa_2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;midwest-post-mortem&#34;&gt;Midwest post-mortem&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week I attended the Midwest Political Science Association annual conference in Chicago. AS conferences go, I was pleased with the event and the payoff was well worth the time and energy it cost to attend. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Close the loops</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/post/close-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/post/close-loops/</guid>
      <description>Last week I presented a best practices workshop on project management for my fellow graduate students. The purpose was to provide younger students in the program with ideas and concepts for managing projects &amp;ldquo;from idea to publication&amp;rdquo;. Preparing my presentation for the workshop afforded me the opportunity to reflect on the principles of productivity that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years. Despite claims to the contrary, both from within and without, the academe is not unlike many other professions: it a profession fundamentally about knowledge work but with functionally infinite demands on otherwise scarce time and attention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Hugo</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/post/hello-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 17:16:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/post/hello-hugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve hosted my webpage on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt; since sometime in my second
year at UT Austin. After several years on the platform, I have nothing
but praise for the folks at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squarespace.com&#34;&gt;Squarespace&lt;/a&gt;: their reputation for
up-time, customer service, and all around technical bad-assery is well
deserved. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking for a web-hosting/web-design company
wherein you can build a beautiful looking site &lt;em&gt;without&lt;/em&gt; knowing &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt;
HTML, CSS, or anything of that stuff&amp;mdash;and I do mean it: without
any&amp;mdash;then you cannot go wrong with a Squarespace site. But for me,
the time has come to say goodbye.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>