<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Luke M Perez</title>
    <link>http://lukemperez.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Luke M Perez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2016 Luke M Perez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 21:21:35 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://lukemperez.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Close the loops</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/project/gtd_writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2016 21:21:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/project/gtd_writing/</guid>
      <description>Summary A short course taught at the Department of Government at the University of Texas at Austin. GitHub Repo includes handout and links of suggested readings (and viewings) on time management, creativity, and best practices. I emphasized the iterative nature of writing, stressing the need to manage the shallow work of email, meetings, and the like so that one can focus un-distracted on the Deep Work of writing, coding, and problem solving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liberating Faith: international religious freedom and American Grand Strategy</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/project/liberating-faith/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 19:46:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/project/liberating-faith/</guid>
      <description>Summary My dissertation investigates the rise of religious liberty in American grand strategy. I begin by noting the empirical oddity of America&amp;rsquo;s international religious freedom agenda vis-a-vis other global powers and argue that religious freedom has long been an integral component to American statecraft. Although religion has recently garnered renewed attention from international relations scholars, the subject remains under-theorized. My project seeks to help us understand more fully how American views of liberty have shaped the efforts to remake and rebuild international order.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>