<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Luke M Perez</title>
    <link>http://lukemperez.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Luke M Perez</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>2016 Luke M Perez</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 08:30:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://lukemperez.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Close the loops</title>
      <link>http://lukemperez.com/post/close-loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2016 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://lukemperez.com/post/close-loops/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I presented a best practices workshop on project management
for my fellow graduate students. The purpose was to provide younger
students in the program with ideas and concepts for managing projects
&amp;ldquo;from idea to publication&amp;rdquo;. Preparing my presentation for the workshop
afforded me the opportunity to reflect on the principles of
productivity that I&amp;rsquo;ve learned over the years. Despite claims to the
contrary, both from within and without, the academe is not unlike
many other professions: it a profession fundamentally about knowledge
work but with functionally infinite demands on otherwise scarce time
and attention. For graduate students in particular, productivity
wastes are especially pernicious because they are so
deceptive. This problem arises from a basic failure to see project
management as anxiety management. Uncompleted tasks and to-do lists,
or worse, half-hearted to-do lists, create a cognitive load on the
mind that destroys the ability to concentrate and get into what Cal
Newport calls &lt;em&gt;deep work&lt;/em&gt;. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the right space to outline the
basics of GTD or any task management system; but whatever system one
uses will work better if we realize the end goal is to free up the
mental bandwidth to concentrate more deeply and more frequently to do
the work that matters to us most.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>