<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>covid on Luke M. Perez, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/covid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in covid on Luke M. Perez, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 09:01:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/covid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Secular Religious Morality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-03-secular-religion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 09:01:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2021-03-secular-religion/</guid>
      <description>Antonio Garcia-Martinez, at his Substack, The Pull Request:
The point isn’t the predictive power of the scientific hypothesis, but how it gets actionably internalized as religious doctrine: It’s possible to speak of objective empirical realities religiously and mythically, and that’s mostly what we do. Note how many climate-change discussions fixate on the flooding aspect of global warming (among the last of the effects we’ll actually see), flooding being a near-universal myth seen everywhere from Native American origin stories to the Greeks, the Hindus, numerous Mesopotamian traditions, and (of course) Genesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic Dialogues</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-03-pandemic-dialogues/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 07:40:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2020-03-pandemic-dialogues/</guid>
      <description>It seems like everyone has new projects during the pandemic. I certainly do. A colleague and I are reading Albert Camus&amp;rsquo;, The Plague, and posting our thoughts as a series of podcast. The first is up now on Podbean, and of course, you can easily find them on your favorite podcast app. Additionally, you can find links to the episodes as they are published, here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
