<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Religious Freedom on Luke M. Perez, Ph.D.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/religious-freedom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Religious Freedom on Luke M. Perez, Ph.D.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 16:11:42 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/religious-freedom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assessing Support for International Religious Freedom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publications/cces-2018-international-religious-freedom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 16:11:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publications/cces-2018-international-religious-freedom/</guid>
      <description>Assessing Support for International Religious Freedom, International Journal of Religious Freedom, 2019. The International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (IRFA) provides the U.S. government with additional tools and information in order to promote the rights of religious minorities around the world. In addition to mandating annual reporting from the State Department, the law created an independent watchdog agency to monitor religious freedom around the world and provides the executive with additional sanction powers for states which abuse religious minorities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPSA, Building the Strategy of Freedom</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/talks/2019_01_spsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 09:30:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/talks/2019_01_spsa/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Building the Strategy of Freedom&amp;rdquo; examines the impact of Jimmy Carter&amp;rsquo;s and Ronald Reagan&amp;rsquo;s national security strategies on international religious freedom. I argue that each attempted to use religious freedom in order to achieve larger national security goals. Carter&amp;rsquo;s moderate success came at a strategic failure (Iranian Revolution and Soviet Invasion of Afghanistan) because he relied on strict substitution of policies. Reagan, however, relied on policy compliments and therefore achieved greater success fusing religious freedom into American grand strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
